

# **TYLER ZEMANTIC**

DIGITAL MEDIA DESIGN & MARKETING | tylerzemantic.com



tyler.zemantic@uconn.edu



860-450-6983



1 Heritage Rd, Columbia CT, 06237

## **PROFILE**

Passionate and driven marketer with entrepreneurial experience in digital media and marketing. Proficient in problem solving and analytical thinking. Highly organized team player who is able perform multiple tasks simultaniously. Enjoys visualizing data and telling a story through the numbers.

### ♣ SKILLS

- Social Media
- Content Strategy
- Branding
- Problem Solving
- Digital Marketing
- Analytics & Analysis
- Web Design/Development
- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Graphic Design
- Photography
- Video Editing
- Communication

### 

- Adobe Creative Suite
- Hootsuite (Certified)
- Google Analytics (Certified)
- Talkwalker Social **Listening (Certified)**
- Salesforce
- WordPress, Wix, Shopify
- Microsoft Office/Excel

### EDUCATION

#### University of Connecticut | GPA: 3.52 | Fall 2019

Studied Digital Media and Design with a concentration in business strategies.

#### School Involvement

The Pound Social Media Analyst AUG 2019 - DEC 2019 **UConn Marketing Society** AUG 2017 - DEC 2019 Huskython Photographer FEB 2017 - FEB 2019



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### UConn DMD x Franklin Sports | Social Media Analyst | Aug 2019 - DEC 2019

At the UConn DMD Social Media Analytics Command Center (SMACC) I worked on the Franklin Sports social media team developing weekly analysis reports. Using programs like Talkwalker, we analyzed data gathered from social media listening platforms to draft statistical narratives that were presented to Franklin Sports social media managers.

#### Aflac | Sales and Marketing Intern | MAY 2019 - AUG 2019

Tracked social media insights and used them to develop reports to work toward creating new public relations strategies. Managed the Capitol Regions Facebook page and created branded content. Met with prospective clients, helped file policies, and continued to manage meaningful relationships with clients.

#### T-Mobile | Media Expert/Retail Sales Associate | Aug 2017 - JAN 2019

Operated register for cash and credit card transactions. Understood customers wants and needs to provide them with the appropriate products and services. Troubleshooted and educated customers about products and services.

#### Top Runner Marketing | Social Media Specialist | MAR 2016 - AUG 2018

Managed social channels and created content for clients. Provided social media insight and developed content strategies and media planning. Also served as an in-house graphic designer, creating content for the agency.